Li Yunxi,
لي يون شي
this jade pendant
قلادة اليشم هذه
was given to me by Mother.
أعطتني إياها والدتي
If you put it on,
إذا ارتديتها
you can never take it off, even in death.
فلا يمكنك خلعها حتى الموت
Alright.
حسنًا
The biggest regret of my life
أكبر ندم في حياتي
is marrying you
هو الزواج منك
and coming to this cage of a palace.
والمجيء إلى هذا القصر الذي يشبه القفص
If I had a second chance,
لو أتيحت لي فرصة ثانية
I'd rather marry Li Yunmo
لفضلت الزواج من لي يون مو
than marry you.
ولن أتزوجك
Want to leave my side?
تريدين مغادرتي
Unless I die.
إلا بموتي
You want me to stay?
أتريدني أن أبقى؟
Don't go.
لا تذهبي
This is the wolf tooth I hunted myself.
هذا ناب ذئب اصطدته بنفسي
It's yours.
أهديه لك
Ling.
آه لينغ
Even if you don't love me,
حتى لو لم تحبيني
I won't let you leave me.
لن أدعك تتركيني
Since ancient times, the strong have ruled over life and death,
منذ القدم، الأقوياء هم من يتحكمون في الحياة والموت
while the lives of the weak are worthless.
بينما حياة الضعفاء لا قيمة لها
Today, I'll show you
اليوم سأجعلك تذوق
what it feels like to have your limbs severed.
مرارة أن تُقطع أطرافك
Empress,
أيتها الإمبراطورة
you lunatic!
أنتِ مجنونة
Stop!
توقفي
Your Majesty, save me.
جلالتك، أنقذني
Empress, what are you doing?
أيتها الإمبراطورة، ما الذي تفعلينه أيضاً؟
Consort Xue, Lady Liu, is so audacious
المحظية شيويه من عشيرة ليو جريئة للغاية
I am merely giving her a small punishment.
أنا فقط أعطيها عقاباً بسيطاً
Your Majesty,
جلالتك
I am innocent.
لقد ظُلمت
I have never even heard of it,
لم أسمع به من قبل
let alone poison the Empress.
ناهيكِ عن تسميم الإمبراطورة
Hanxing.
هان شينغ
Your Majesty.
يا صاحب الجلالة.
This is the medicine bottle I found in Feixue Palace.
هذه زجاجة الدواء التي وجدتها في قصر الثلج المتساقط.
Empress, you...
أيتها الإمبراطورة، أنتِ...
You are just envious that I
أنتِ فقط تحسدينني
possess His Majesty's favor.
لأنني أحظى بحب جلالته.
Su Kuang,
سو كوانغ.
check what's inside this bottle.
تحقق مما يوجد في هذه الزجاجة.
Yes.
أمرك.
Your Majesty,
يا صاحب الجلالة.
I have been wrongly accused.
لقد اتُهمتُ ظلمًا.
Please do justice for me.
أتوسل إلى جلالتكم أن تنصفوني.
The Empress has killed someone!
الإمبراطورة قتلت شخصًا.
Your Majesty,
أيها الإمبراطور.
the deceased is Ruyan, a maid from Jile Hall.
القتيلة هي الخادمة رويان من قصر النعيم.
She has been missing for two days.
لقد اختفت منذ يومين.
The Empress has been looking for her.
وكانت الإمبراطورة تبحث عنها باستمرار.
When she was found,
عندما عُثر عليها.
she had been dead for a long time.
كانت قد فارقت الحياة منذ فترة طويلة.
Why have I heard rumors about the Empress?
كيف سمعت بعض الشائعات عن الإمبراطورة؟
A dagger was stuck in the deceased's chest,
كان هناك خنجر مغروس في صدر القتيلة.
and she was holding a medicine bottle.
وكانت تمسك بقارورة دواء في يدها.
After the Imperial Physician's examination,
بعد فحص الطبيب الإمبراطوري،
it was said that the bottle once contained Qingsirao.
قيل إن زجاجة الدواء كانت تحتوي على "خيوط الحب".
Rumor has it that
هناك شائعات تقول
the Empress was jealous of Consort Xue's favor,
إن الإمبراطورة غارت من حظوة المحظية شيويه لدى جلالته،
so she used Qingsirao to frame her.
فاستخدمت "خيوط الحب" لتوريطها.
Unexpectedly, the plot was exposed.
لكن بشكل غير متوقع، انكشف أمرها.
In a fit of rage, the Empress
فغضبت الإمبراطورة،
killed the witness, Ruyan, to silence her.
وقتلت رو يان التي تعرف الحقيقة لإسكاتها.
His Majesty has arrived.
وصول جلالة الإمبراطور.
What brings Your Majesty here?
ما الذي أتى بجلالتكم إلى هنا؟
I heard you are investigating Ruyan.
سمعت أنكِ تحققين في أمر رو يان.
So, Your Majesty has come to interrogate me.
إذًا جلالتكم هنا لمعاقبتي.
What secret is Ruyan hiding?
ما هو السر الذي تخفيه رويان؟
You've been acting strange lately.
تصرفاتك غريبة مؤخراً.
You're not usually so aggressive.
لستِ من النوع العدواني.
Then, Your Majesty,
جلالتك، في النهاية
do you believe I am innocent?
هل تصدق أنني بريئة أم لا؟
I mean,
ما أعنيه هو
everything requires evidence.
أن كل شيء يجب أن يستند إلى الأدلة.
Does evidence really matter?
هل الأدلة مفيدة حقاً؟
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعلين؟
You trust Consort Xue so much.
أنت تثق كثيراً في المحظية شيويه.
Is it because
هل هذا لأنها
she knows how to pretend to be gentle
تجيد التظاهر باللطف
and pitiful?
وإثارة الشفقة؟
You are my woman.
أنتِ امرأتي،
I won't let Li Yunmo have you.
ومن المستحيل أن أتنازل عنكِ لـ لي يون مو.
Yunmo.
يون مو...
Calling his name late at night,
تنادين باسمه في وقت متأخر من الليل
and so intimately too.
وبكل هذه الحميمية.
I...
أنا...
Get out.
اخرجي.
You're crazy.
أأنت مجنون؟
You were the one who brought up Li Yunmo.
أنت من ذكرت لي يون مو أولاً.
Fine, I'm leaving.
سأرحل إذاً.
Your Highness.
صاحبة السمو.
Wait.
لحظة،
You should be the one leaving.
أنت من يجب أن يرحل.
This is my Jile Hall.
هذا قصر السعادة خاصتي.
Return to the palace.
عودوا إلى القصر.
Lunatic.
مجنون.
Greetings, Your Majesty.
تحية لجلالتك.
I said I could show you favor,
لقد قلت أنه يمكنني تدليلكِ.
but you must not cause trouble at the Hall of Bliss.
ولكن لا يمكنكِ الذهاب إلى قصر النعيم لإثارة المتاعب.
You rarely visit me, Your Majesty.
من النادر أن يأتي جلالتك إلى هنا.
Did you come just to scold me?
هل أتيت فقط لتوبيخي؟
I am just a weak woman.
أنا مجرد امرأة ضعيفة.
How could I take a life?
كيف لي أن أفعل شيئًا يؤذي حياة الناس؟
Liu Mianmian.
ليو ميان ميان.
Just because I don't expose you doesn't mean I don't know.
عدم فضحي لكِ لا يعني أنني لا أعرف.
You'd better not forget why I married you.
من الأفضل ألا تنسي لماذا تزوجتكِ.
It's just a transaction.
كل منا يأخذ ما يحتاجه من الآخر.
Your Majesty.
جلالتك.
I just care about you too much,
أنا فقط أهتم بك كثيراً
so that is why I was jealous of the Empress.
لذلك أغار من الإمبراطورة.
I won't disobey you again.
أعدك أنني لن أعصي أوامرك بعد الآن.
Please don't be angry with me, alright?
أرجوك لا تغضب مني، حسنًا؟
Her Majesty the Empress has arrived.
وصول جلالة الإمبراطورة.
Your Majesty.
جلالتك.
Look at my hands.
انظر إلى يدي.
I often soak them in rose water.
أنقعها دائمًا في ماء الورد.
Aren't they fragrant
أليست عطرةً
and soft?
وناعمة؟
I apologize for disturbing your leisure, Your Majesty.
أعتذر عن مقاطعة جلالتك.
I have come for an important matter.
أتيت لأمر مهم.
What is it?
ما الأمر؟
Come in.
ادخل.
Imperial Physician Wang,
أيها الطبيب الإمبراطوري وانغ.
please explain the cause of Ruyan's death to His Majesty.
من فضلك، اشرح لجلالته سبب وفاة رو يان.
Your Majesty.
جلالتك.
The deceased, Ruyan, had foam in her mouth and nose,
وُجد زبد في فم وأنف المتوفاة رو يان،
and slight bleeding in her ears.
مع نزيف طفيف في أذنيها.
The knife wound on her chest was deep,
جرح الطعن في صدرها كان عميقًا،
but there was very little bleeding.
لكن لم يكن هناك سوى نزيف قليل.
Her cause of death was not the stab wound,
سبب وفاتها لم يكن طعنة الصدر هذه،
but asphyxiation caused by drowning.
بل ماتت اختناقًا بسبب الغرق.